Abhishek Singh

Email: abhishek.singhbit11@gmail.com, Mob: 9513142884

GitHub: - mike2k11 (github.com) LinkedIn: - www.linkedin.com/in/abhishek-singh10

To be a well-versed techie and to fulfill my responsibilities through sheer commitment and hard work that helps in my development as well as organization through perpetual learning.

An Ambitious Problem Solver and Result-oriented webapi Developer with considerable training and enterprise experience in API design, Machine Learning Models. Layout in all states of design, coding, and testing of the web services, and in the formation, planning, and implementation of the online business ventures. Working gives me a lot of skills and experience that I believe make me more confident. Analytical thinking and Problem solving attitude. Always try to Learn and Update myself with latest skills and Technology.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION			
Degree	Percentage	Institute/University	Year Of Passing
B.E (ELECTRONIC & COMMUNICATIONS)	7 CGPA (Degree)	BIRLA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, MESRA	May-2015
H.S.C. (CBSE)	82.20%	D.A.V Public School	May-2010
S.S.C. (CBSE)	86.60%	St Xavier School	May-2008

Professional Summary And Technical Skills

I have a total 6 years of professional IT experience starting carrier in Infosys and then PwC. where I have worked on Multiple stacks right from Python, DataStructures (Stack,Queues,LinkedList), Django, Flask, SqlAlchemy ORM, RestAPI, Web Scraping Library Scrapy and BeautifullSoup, Wrangling/Processing/visualization, Machine learning Algorithm, Git, Linux Environment, MS-SQL and SAP.

I have a basic understanding of Docker, kubernetes, Ansible, AWS services, Scikit Learn Library, NLP, Spacy and other Libraries, Gensim-TFIDF, Sentiment Analysis, Word Embedding, Deep learning(RNN-LSTM), HTML, Excel, Networking, SAP ABAP, SAP-HCM (SF).

I have been a part of Organizations Internal society working for Fun activities for the kids and Employees at different occasions as well as volunteering in CSR in Tree plantation as well as Social awareness programs.

WORK HISTORY

HCL Technologies – Pune May2021-Present

Technology Lead

Project Description1: CIF, Cloud Infra | | Client: Cisco

Docker Compose file creation for the webservices deployment and managing them, working on AWS services.

Technology used: Docker, AWS Services, Kubernetes, Python, Ansible.

PwC Kolkata February 2020 - March 2021

Senior Associate

Project1: GDH|| Client: PwC Global

Developed a Rest API using Flask Framework for Data consumption from MS-SQL database. Created Multiple Python Script solution for data Processing. Understood the Business Part and Performed troubleshooting by changed the existing Code and adding new functionality written in Django Framework. Fully responsible for the deliverables. I was also involved Month Cycle activities with Data Engineering Team where our Task was to Run Running Scripts written in SQL to consume the data file Upload by 143 Territories and Inserting them into Corresponding Tables in Different databases by transforming them using ETL tool such SSIS.

Technology used: Python, OOPs Concept, Flask, Multithreading, SSIS ETL Tool.

Developed Multiple KPIs for the BBMP Bengaluru. BBMP wanted us to create Dashboard about all the People who were coming into Bangalore Post Lockdown and taking Quarantine in Public and Private Hotels. For Example Person Name, where they are staying(Facility Name), Total Quarantined people, Total Discharged, Covid Positive etc Datewise. Created Reports on PowerBI. Consumption of data from Multiple Sources as CDS, SQL etc and Created Dashboard and Published Tools and Technology used: Microsoft PowerBI, SQL, Excel CDS PowerApps.

Infosys Pune Sept'2015-Feb 2020

Technology Analyst

Project#1: - MFGADM | | Client: Cisco

Our Project was a part of the Journey Automation for Identifying Potential Customers and actual customers for a particular Hardware and Software products and sending them the marketing emails. The content of each emails depends on the product and common customer details. For all these work we were sourcing the data for each product campaign, Creating and Running Python Scripts for different Campaigns, filtering out Customer data based on Business Rules. QA Automation. Once the data is sourced and processed in Hadoop, the data is activated and deployed on a marketing tool names Eloqua through which Scheduled Marketing emails are sent to the customers.

Project#2: - MFGADM || Ticket Sentiments Analysis || CoE

Worked on Multiple Projects where I developed Machine Learning Models based Data wrangling, processing, analysis and data visualization. Creating Predictive Model using Machine Learning Algorithm for e.g.- Linear regression, Logistic, Decision Tree, KMeans, KNN classifier, PCA etc. Hyper-parameter Tuning Using Grid Search and Random Search, Confusion matrix, Cross Validation.

Tools and Technology used: Python ML libraries eg:- Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Nltk etc, Jupyter Notebook.

Project#3: IoT and WebScraping | | Client: Infosys POC Project

In this Team I worked on Multiple PoCs based on IOT, webscraping etc. Successfully Connected Raspberrypi with Heat sensor, RFID Module alongwith other sensors. Collected data for processing.

Designed and implemented a framework for webscraping

Technology used: PowerBI, Azure Machine Learning, React JS, Redux.

Graduate Trainee, Sept15-Mar16

Infosys Ltd- Mysore

Training braced my skills both professionally as well as technically. To work as an engineer in Infosys, one has to clear the tests taken by Infosys and later a band is provided according to the cumulative performance in all tests. I was given HPF band (for 91%) in their training.

Technology used: Python, SQL, SAP ABAP, SAP HCM(SF).

Hobbies:

Swimming, Badminton, Running, Pool&Snooker, Trekking.

Personal Details:

Abhishek Singh (D.O.B – 10th June 1993) Ranchi, Jharkhand Language – English, Hindi.